Guide to the Olga Rudge Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Series V, Financial Papers, contains a variety of material documenting financial transactions made by Rudge between 1926 and 1989. Most of the papers are post-1962 and include bank statements and receipts, utility bills, restaurant checks, hotel bills, and transportation tickets. Box 121, folder 2988 contains papers concerning Pound's funeral expenses. Leases for three of Rudge's residences can be found in Box 125, folders 3057-59, and information on royalties from Pound's works received by Rudge is located in folders 3060-65. Box 125, folder 3054, holds papers relating to Rudge's claim for war reparations arising from damage to her house in Venice. Rudge's long and unsatisfactory investment in half of a parking lot in Youngstown, Ohio (an inheritance from her father), is chronicled in Box 126, folders 3073-79.
Series VI, Printed Material, consists largely of miscellaneous printed matter collected by Rudge. Propaganda leaflets dropped on Rapallo by the Saló regime in 1943 are located in Box 33, folder 3173. Folders 3158-70 contain material relating to Ezra Pound, mainly announcements of conferences and exhibitions held after his death and photocopies of various articles concerning him. There are seventeen folders of pamphlets, flyers, and other promotional material related to art galleries and exhibitions, mostly dating from the 1970s and 1980s, and six folders of announcements and circulars for the Fondazione Giorgio Cini.
Rudge was an assiduous collector of newspaper clippings as well, and these fill seven boxes as Series VII, organized alphabetically by subject. (Clippngs concerning Rudge's musical career can be found in Series VIII, Music.) A large number of these concern Ezra Pound, and include biographical profiles, interviews, reviews of works by and about him, and obituaries. Box 140, folders 3312-13, contain scrapbooks of articles both about Pound and sent by Pound to Olga Rudge from St. Elizabeth's Hospital in the late 1940s, similar to the clippings still filed with the Pound-Rudge correspondence in Series I. Rudge's interest in literature is reflected in the more than forty folders of clippings concerning various modern authors, arranged alphabetically by author under the heading "Literature."
Other subjects include "Fascism/World War II," "Politics and Economics," and "Psychiatry," which includes a folder of items on the theories of Thomas Szasz.
Series VIII, Music, documents Olga Rudge's musical career and interests. A scrapbook of notices and clippings concerning Rudge's early performances can be found in Box 146, folders 3426-32. Box 145, folders 3413-20, holds "Announcements and Programs" for many of her performances from 1913 until 1937. Included are the programs for her Pound and Antheil concerts in the 1920s and for many of her performances of modern Italian music and Vivaldi throughout her career. The history of the Concerti Tigulliani is documented in folders 3367-79; material includes announcements of programs, flyers and other publicity, and clippings of Il Mare articles by Pound, Basil Bunting, and Desmond Chute. Folder 3370 contains information on the later "Inverno musicale nel Tigullio."
Rudge's dedication to her work on Antonio Vivaldi was so apparent that her employer, conte Chigi-Saracini, often introduced her as "Signorina Rudge-Vivaldi." The Vivaldi section of Series VIII includes materials related to her unsuccessful applications for a Guggenheim Fellowship, a list of scores at the library at Turin, notes, and notebooks. There are also notes and typescripts by both Rudge and Pound concerning the microfilming of Vivaldi scores, and four folders of empty photograph envelopes annotated by both.
Perhaps the most interesting manuscripts in this series are Rudge's collection of autograph scores. George Antheil, her early partner, is represented by signed scores for Sonata for Solo Violin, Sonata for Violin and Fortepiano: for Olga Rudge, and Troisième Sonate pour violon et piano: for Mrs. Christian Gross. There are also many pages of Vivaldi arrangements and partial scores in the hands of Rudge, Pound, Gerhart Münch, Julia Perry, and perhaps Tibor Serly, ranging in date from the mid-1930s to the late 1950s, in the case of the Perry scores.
The series also contains a variety of printed material and printed scores, as well as clippings and concert announcements documenting Antheil's performances in the late 1920s.
Series IX, Photographs, is housed in Boxes 148-154 and contains photographs of Rudge, Pound, their family and friends, and miscellaneous places and objects. (Photographs pertaining to Rudge's parents and early childhood can be found in Series X, Family Papers).
There are two albums. The earlier, labeled "Capri 1921," is the photographic record of a summer Rudge spent on Capri with Renata Borgatti and other friends, including Maria Favai, Lindy Shaw-Paige, and Mimy Franchetti, some of whose activities furnished material for Compton Mackenzie's Extraordinary Women. The shots include portraits, beach scenes, and pantomime poses in "Grecian" robes.
Box 148, folders 3478-89, contains snapshots from an album originally labelled "Album 2" by Rudge. Apparently dating from the mid-1920s to the mid-1930s, the photographs feature Rudge, Pound, and their daughter Mary in various settings, particularly Venice and Gais.
The majority of photographs in the series feature Ezra Pound and Olga Rudge, alone or with others; most of these are undated and have been arranged first by subject and then according to rough chronological order. Most of the photographs of both date from the last ten years of Pound's life, although each is represented by some earlier portraits.
Boxes 152 and 153 contain photographs of people and places. Notable persons include George Antheil, represented by autographed studio portraits; Renata Borgatti; Katherine Dalliba-John; Benito Mussolini (autographed to Rudge, 1933); Ildebrando Pizzetti; and Mary de Rachewiltz and her family. Folders 3570-77 contain photos of unidentified persons. Places illustrated include Hailey, Idaho, and Rudge's home in Venice. Box 154 contains photos of miscellaneous subjects.
Series X, Family Papers, consists of two boxes of material documenting the Rudge family. There are about two dozen letters to and from various family members, including letters to Julia O'Connell Rudge from Mabel and Ethel Duncan and a letter from Teddy Rudge to Santa Claus; records of World War I service of Arthur and Teddy Rudge; and four folders of papers concerning Julia O'Connell Rudge's singing career, particularly a scrapbook of notices and a publicity brochure for the Delle Sedie School of Singing. There are also two Rudge family albums, containing many portraits taken during Olga's childhood, and three folders of portraits of Julia O'Connell Rudge.
Series XI, Ezra Pound Foundation, is one box of material material that was formerly restricted until 2016. Legally privileged documents and legal documents that by their terms were governed by confidentiality clauses have been redacted from files P: Negotiations with Yale and Q: Closing documents.
.
American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Modernism (Literature); Poets, American -- 20th Century; Women violinists; Agresti, Olivia Rossetti, 1875-1960; Antheil, George, 1900-1959; Bacigalupo, Massimo, 1947-; Barilli, Bruno, 1880-1952; Barney, Natalie Clifford, 1877-1972; Borgatti, Renata; Brown, Arturo; Casella, Alfredo, 1883-1947; Connolly, Cyril, 1903-1974; Dazzi, Manlio (Manlio Torquato), 1891-1968; Drummond, John; Duncan, Ethel; Duncan, Ronald C., 1936-; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965; Fitzgerald, Robert, 1910-1985; Grey, Egerton Charles; Ivancich, Gianfranco; Jordan, Viola Baxter, 1887-1973; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997; Littlefield, Lester; Muench, Gerhart; O'Grady, Desmond, 1935-; Paige, Douglas D.; Pea, Enrico, 1881-1958; Perry, Julia; Pizzetti, Ildebrando, 1880-1968; Polignac, Winnaretta, princesse de, 1865-1943; Pound, Dorothy; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972; Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1925-; Rainer, Dachine; Rudge, Olga, 1895-1996; Russell, Peter, 1921-2003; Schneider, Edouard, 1880-; Serly, Tibor, 1901-1978; Slavin, George; Stokes, Adrian, 1902-1972; Swabey, Henry; Vivaldi, Antonio, 1678-1741; Wykes-Joyce, Max; Chigi Saracini, Guido, conte, 1880-1965; Dalliba-John, Katherine
- Rudge-Pound Correspondence, 1923-69; Series I; 15.75; (32 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Rudge-Pound Correspondence, is housed in Boxes 1-32 and contains chronologically arranged correspondence between Olga Rudge and Ezra Pound.
  - Correspondence, 1923 Jun-Oct (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1923 Nov-Dec (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, [1923?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Jan (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Feb (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Mar (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Apr (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1924 May (Box 1, Folder 8-12)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Jun (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Oct (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Nov (Box 1, Folder 17-21)
  - Correspondence, 1924 Dec (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
  - Correspondence, [1924?] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Mar (Box 1, Folder 27-29)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Apr (Box 2, Folder 30-32)
  - Correspondence, 1925 May (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Jun (Box 2, Folder 35-37)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Jul (Box 2, Folder 38-41)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Aug (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Sep (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Oct (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Nov (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
  - Correspondence, 1925 Dec (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, [1925?] (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, 1926 Feb (Box 2, Folder 50-51)
  - Correspondence, 1926 Mar (Box 2, Folder 52-55)
  - Correspondence, 1926 [Mar-Apr?] (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, 1926 Apr (Box 3, Folder 57-61)
  - Correspondence, 1926 May (Box 3, Folder 62-63)
  - Correspondence, 1926 Jun, Sep (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence, 1926 Oct (Box 3, Folder 65-67)
  - Correspondence, 1926 Nov (Box 3, Folder 68-72)
  - Correspondence, 1926 Dec (Box 3, Folder 73-74)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Jan (Box 3, Folder 75-79)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Feb (Box 3, Folder 80-85)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Mar (Box 4, Folder 86-91)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Apr (Box 4, Folder 92-95)
  - Correspondence, 1927 May (Box 4, Folder 96-98)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Jul (Box 4, Folder 99-100)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Aug (Box 4, Folder 101-04)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Sep (Box 4, Folder 105-07)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Oct (Box 4, Folder 108-13)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Nov (Box 5, Folder 114-17)
  - Correspondence, 1927 Dec (Box 5, Folder 118-20)
  - Correspondence, [1927?] (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Jan (Box 5, Folder 122-23)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Feb (Box 5, Folder 124-28)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Mar (Box 5, Folder 129-36)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Apr (Box 6, Folder 137-42)
  - Correspondence, 1928 [Apr?] (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Correspondence, 1928 May (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Jun (Box 6, Folder 145-46)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Jul (Box 6, Folder 147-54)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Aug (Box 6, Folder 155-61)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Sep (Box 7, Folder 162-65)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Oct (Box 7, Folder 166-68)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Nov (Box 7, Folder 169-73)
  - Correspondence, 1928 Dec (Box 7, Folder 174-77)
  - Correspondence, [1928?] (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Jan (Box 7, Folder 179-81)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Feb (Box 7, Folder 182-84)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Mar (Box 8, Folder 185-87)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Jul (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Aug (Box 8, Folder 189-93)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Sep (Box 8, Folder 194-95)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Oct (Box 8, Folder 196-98)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Nov (Box 8, Folder 199-202)
  - Correspondence, 1929 [Nov?] (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - Correspondence, 1929 Dec (Box 8, Folder 204-07)
  - Correspondence, [1920s?] (Box 8, Folder 208-09)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Jan (Box 9, Folder 210-16)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Feb (Box 9, Folder 217)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Mar (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Apr (Box 9, Folder 219)
  - Correspondence, 1930 May (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Jul (Box 9, Folder 221)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Aug (Box 9, Folder 222-27)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Sep (Box 9, Folder 228-30)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Oct (Box 9, Folder 231-34)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Nov (Box 9, Folder 235-36)
  - Correspondence, 1930 Dec (Box 10, Folder 237-44)
  - Correspondence, [1930?] (Box 10, Folder 245)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Jan (Box 10, Folder 246-48)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Feb (Box 10, Folder 249-51)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Mar (Box 10, Folder 252-57)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Apr (Box 10, Folder 258)
  - Correspondence, 1931 May (Box 10, Folder 259)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Jun (Box 10, Folder 260-65)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Jul (Box 11, Folder 266-70)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Aug (Box 11, Folder 271-77)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Sep (Box 11, Folder 278-83)
  - Correspondence, 1931 Dec (Box 11, Folder 284-90)
  - Correspondence, [1931?] (Box 11, Folder 291)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Jan (Box 12, Folder 292-98)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Feb (Box 12, Folder 299-305)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Mar (Box 12, Folder 306)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Apr (Box 12, Folder 307-11)
  - Correspondence, 1932 May (Box 12, Folder 312-18)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Jun (Box 13, Folder 319)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Jul-Aug (Box 13, Folder 320)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Aug (Box 13, Folder 321)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Oct (Box 13, Folder 322)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 13, Folder 323-28)
  - Correspondence, 1932 Dec (Box 13, Folder 329-31)
  - Correspondence, [1932?] (Box 13, Folder 332)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Jan (Box 13, Folder 333-35)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Feb (Box 13, Folder 336)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Mar (Box 13, Folder 337-40)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Apr (Box 13, Folder 341-47)
  - Correspondence, 1933 May (Box 14, Folder 348-49)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Jul (Box 14, Folder 350-52)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Aug (Box 14, Folder 353-56)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Sep (Box 14, Folder 357-59)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Oct (Box 14, Folder 360-62)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Nov (Box 14, Folder 363)
  - Correspondence, 1933 Dec (Box 14, Folder 364-67)
  - Correspondence, [1933] (Box 14, Folder 368)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Jan (Box 14, Folder 369-74)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Feb (Box 15, Folder 375-80)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Mar (Box 15, Folder 381)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Apr (Box 15, Folder 382-83)
  - Correspondence, 1934 May (Box 15, Folder 384)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Jun (Box 15, Folder 385)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Aug-Sep (Box 15, Folder 386)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Oct (Box 15, Folder 387-92)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Nov (Box 15, Folder 393-94)
  - Correspondence, 1934 Dec (Box 15, Folder 395-400)
  - Correspondence, [1934] (Box 15, Folder 401)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Jan (Box 15, Folder 402-05)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Feb-Mar (Box 15, Folder 406)
  - Correspondence, 1935 May (Box 16, Folder 407-08)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Apr (Box 16, Folder 409)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Jun-Aug (Box 16, Folder 410)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Sep (Box 16, Folder 411-13)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Oct (Box 16, Folder 414-19)
  - Correspondence, 1935 Dec (Box 16, Folder 420-23)
  - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 424)
  - Correspondence, [1935?] (Box 16, Folder 425)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Jan (Box 16, Folder 426-30)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Feb (Box 16, Folder 431-35)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Mar (Box 16, Folder 436)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Apr (Box 17, Folder 437)
  - Correspondence, 1936 May (Box 17, Folder 438)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Jun (Box 17, Folder 439-40)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Jul (Box 17, Folder 441-44)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Aug-Sep (Box 17, Folder 445)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Oct (Box 17, Folder 446-48)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Nov (Box 17, Folder 449-53)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Dec (Box 17, Folder 454)
  - Correspondence, [1936?] (Box 17, Folder 455)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Jan (Box 17, Folder 456)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Feb (Box 17, Folder 457)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Mar (Box 17, Folder 458)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Apr (Box 17, Folder 459)
  - Correspondence, 1937 May (Box 17, Folder 460-61)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Jun (Box 17, Folder 462-63)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Jul (Box 17, Folder 464-69)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Sep (Box 18, Folder 470)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Oct (Box 18, Folder 471-73)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Nov (Box 18, Folder 474)
  - Correspondence, 1937 Dec (Box 18, Folder 475)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 476)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Jan (Box 18, Folder 477-78)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Feb (Box 18, Folder 479)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Mar (Box 18, Folder 480-83)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Apr-May (Box 18, Folder 484)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Jun (Box 18, Folder 485)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Jul (Box 18, Folder 486-89)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Aug (Box 18, Folder 490-92)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Sep (Box 18, Folder 493-98)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Oct (Box 19, Folder 499-504)
  - Correspondence, 1938 Nov (Box 19, Folder 505-08)
  - Correspondence, [1938 Dec] (Box 19, Folder 509)
  - Correspondence, [1938?] (Box 19, Folder 510)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Jan (Box 19, Folder 511)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Feb (Box 19, Folder 512-15)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Mar (Box 19, Folder 516)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Apr (Box 19, Folder 517-18)
  - Correspondence, 1939 May (Box 19, Folder 519-24)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Jun (Box 19, Folder 525-29)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Jul (Box 20, Folder 530-32)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Aug (Box 20, Folder 533-34)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Sep (Box 20, Folder 535-37)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Oct (Box 20, Folder 538)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Nov (Box 20, Folder 539)
  - Correspondence, 1939 Dec (Box 20, Folder 540)
  - Correspondence, [1939?] (Box 20, Folder 541)
  - Correspondence, [1930s?] (Box 20, Folder 542-46)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Jan-Feb (Box 20, Folder 547)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Mar (Box 20, Folder 548)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Apr (Box 20, Folder 549-50)
  - Correspondence, 1940 May (Box 20, Folder 551)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Jun (Box 20, Folder 552)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Jul (Box 20, Folder 553-60)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Aug (Box 20, Folder 561-64)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Sep (Box 21, Folder 565-66)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Oct (Box 21, Folder 567-74)
  - Correspondence, 1940 Nov (Box 21, Folder 575)
  - Correspondence, [1940?] (Box 21, Folder 576)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Jan (Box 21, Folder 577)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Feb (Box 21, Folder 578-79)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Mar (Box 21, Folder 580)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Apr (Box 21, Folder 581-82)
  - Correspondence, 1941 May (Box 21, Folder 583-84)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Jun (Box 21, Folder 585)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Jul (Box 21, Folder 586-90)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 21, Folder 591-92)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Sep (Box 21, Folder 593-95)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Oct (Box 21, Folder 596-99)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 22, Folder 600)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Dec (Box 22, Folder 601)
  - Correspondence, [1941?] (Box 22, Folder 602)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Jan (Box 22, Folder 603-04)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 605)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Mar (Box 22, Folder 606-09)
  - Correspondence, 1942 May (Box 22, Folder 610)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Jun (Box 22, Folder 611-12)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Jul (Box 22, Folder 613)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Aug (Box 22, Folder 614)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Sep (Box 22, Folder 615-16)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Oct (Box 22, Folder 617-18)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 619-20)
  - Correspondence, 1942 Dec (Box 22, Folder 621-22)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Jan (Box 22, Folder 623)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Feb (Box 22, Folder 624)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Mar (Box 22, Folder 625-26)
  - Correspondence, 1943 May (Box 22, Folder 627-29)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Jun (Box 23, Folder 630-31)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Jul (Box 23, Folder 632)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Aug-Oct (Box 23, Folder 633)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Nov (Box 23, Folder 634)
  - Correspondence, 1943 Dec (Box 23, Folder 635-36)
  - Correspondence, [1943] (Box 23, Folder 637)
  - Correspondence, [1944] (Box 23, Folder 638)
  - Correspondence, [1945] (Box 23, Folder 639)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: Box 83, folder 2238
  - Correspondence, [1940-45?] (Box 23, Folder 640)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Jan (Box 23, Folder 641)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Feb (Box 23, Folder 642)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Mar (Box 23, Folder 643-44)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Apr (Box 23, Folder 645-47)
  - Correspondence, 1946 May (Box 23, Folder 648)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Jun (Box 23, Folder 649-50)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Jul (Box 23, Folder 651-53)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Aug (Box 23, Folder 654-56)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Sep (Box 23, Folder 657-58)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Oct (Box 24, Folder 659-61)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Nov (Box 24, Folder 662-64)
  - Correspondence, 1946 Dec (Box 24, Folder 665-68)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Jan (Box 24, Folder 669)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Feb (Box 24, Folder 670-72)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Mar (Box 24, Folder 673-76)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Apr (Box 24, Folder 677-79)
  - Correspondence, 1947 May (Box 24, Folder 680-81)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Jun (Box 24, Folder 682)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Jul (Box 24, Folder 683)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Aug (Box 24, Folder 684)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Sep (Box 24, Folder 685-86)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Oct (Box 24, Folder 687)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Nov (Box 25, Folder 688-89)
  - Correspondence, 1947 Dec (Box 25, Folder 690-91)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Jan (Box 25, Folder 692-94)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Feb (Box 25, Folder 695-97)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Mar (Box 25, Folder 698-700)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Apr (Box 25, Folder 701-03)
  - Correspondence, 1948 May (Box 25, Folder 704-06)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Jun (Box 25, Folder 707-08)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Jul (Box 25, Folder 709-10)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Aug (Box 25, Folder 711-13)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Sep (Box 25, Folder 714-16)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Oct (Box 25, Folder 717-18)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Nov (Box 26, Folder 719-21)
  - Correspondence, 1948 Dec (Box 26, Folder 722-24)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Jan (Box 26, Folder 725-27)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Feb (Box 26, Folder 728-29)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Mar (Box 26, Folder 730)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Apr (Box 26, Folder 731-32)
  - Correspondence, 1949 May (Box 26, Folder 733-34)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Jun (Box 26, Folder 735-36)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Jul (Box 26, Folder 737-38)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Aug (Box 26, Folder 739)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Sep (Box 26, Folder 740-43)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Oct (Box 26, Folder 744-45)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Nov (Box 26, Folder 746-47)
  - Correspondence, 1949 Dec (Box 26, Folder 748-49)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Jan (Box 27, Folder 750-51)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Feb (Box 27, Folder 752-53)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Mar (Box 27, Folder 754)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Apr (Box 27, Folder 755-56)
  - Correspondence, 1950 May (Box 27, Folder 757)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Jun (Box 27, Folder 758-59)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Jul (Box 27, Folder 760-61)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Aug (Box 27, Folder 762-64)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Sep (Box 27, Folder 765)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Oct (Box 27, Folder 766)
  - Correspondence, 1950 Nov (Box 27, Folder 767-68)